https://www.milligan.edu/privacy-policy/

COVID Response
MILLIGAN RETURNS HOME - COVID RESPONSE »
X
HomeAboutAbout MilliganFast FactsMission & VisionDirectoryLeadershipNationally RecognizedHistory & HeritageEmploymentSafety & SecurityConsumer InformationLocationCampus MapVirtual TourOur RegionDirections to CampusRegional AirportsRegional AccommodationsThompson Community CenterCampus HoursContact Us!Refer a StudentCampus DirectoryContact us800.262.8337FacebookTwitter CloseAcademicsOVERVIEWDEGREES & PROGRAMS »Accelerated ProgramsGraduate & Professional ProgramsEmmanuel Christian SeminarySchoolsFacultyChristian Liberal ArtsCore Curriculum – GERAccreditation & ReputationThe Humanities ProgramThe Milligan Honors ProgramStudy AbroadUndergraduate ResearchDiversity at MilliganRESOURCESAcademic Staff & OfficesCatalogFaculty DirectorySchedules & CalendarsAdvisingCourse SequencesWriting SampleCommencementLibrariesInformation TechnologyBookstoreTranscript Request FormCareer DevelopmentStudent SuccessDisability ServicesConcerns & Issues CloseAdmissionUNDERGRAD ADMISSIONApply NowVisit MilliganRequest InfoScholarships & CostForms & PublicationsStaffFirst-Time StudentsTransfersHomeschool StudentsInternationalsVeteransDual EnrollmentAdmitted StudentsParentsGRADUATE ADMISSIONAccelerated Bachelor’s to Master’s ProgramsMaster of Arts in Humanities (MAH)Master of Business Administration (MBA)Master of Education (MEd)Master of Science in Counseling (MSC)Master of Science in Information Systems (MSIS)Master of Science in Occupational Therapy (MSOT)Master of Science in Physician Assistant Studies (MSPAS)Doctor of Education (EdD/EdS)EMMANUEL CHRISTIAN SEMINARYMaster of Arts in Religion (MAR)Master of Arts in Christian Ministries (MACM)Master of Divinity (MDiv)Doctor of Ministry (DMin)DEGREE COMPLETIONBusiness Administration (BSBA)Child & Youth Development (Early Ed)Information Systems (IS)RN-BSN (Accelerated)Contact Us!Refer a StudentCampus DirectoryContact us800.262.8337FacebookTwitter CloseStudent LifeCOMMUNITY LIFECampus Events CalendarMilligan TodayClubs & OrganizationsSGAThe Stampede OnlineWUMC Milligan College RadioCareer DevelopmentDiversity at MilliganConcerns & IssuesStudent HandbookHOUSING & DININGResidence Halls & ApartmentsDining at MilliganDining Announcements & MenusCampus HoursCommutersFinancial AidHEALTH & WELLNESSGilliam Wellness CenterMilligan Counseling CenterHealth ServicesSafety & SecurityStudent SuccessFAITH & WORSHIPCampus MinistrySpiritual Formation ProgramService at MilliganSeeger Memorial ChapelChurch Resources CloseAlumni & FriendsALUMNI & FRIENDSTranscript Request FormChange Address or Submit a Class NoteMilligan Online CommunityCareer DevelopmentMilligan MagazineShare a Milligan StoryBe a Buff Club – for kidsAssociated Ladies for MilliganParentsCHURCH RELATIONSWhy support Milligan?Campus MinistryService at MilliganOpen Ministry PositionsHeritage singing groupSUPPORT MILLIGANThe Milligan FundForward Ever: The Campaign for MilliganEstablishing Scholarship FundsThe Buffalo ClubGive OnlineRESOURCESBookstoreLand’s End – Milligan gear“Be a Buff” Summer CampsCollege Leadership CloseAthleticsFaculty & StaffNews & EventsNewsRecent NewsAthletic NewsCampus AnnouncementsNews ArchivesMilligan MagazinePublic Relations & MarketingEvents at MilliganCampus CalendarFaith, Arts & Culture EventsAlumni EventsAdmission EventsYouth Summer CampsContact Us!Refer a StudentCampus DirectoryContact us800.262.8337FacebookTwitterRecent NewsGive A Gift That Makes An ImpactNovember 30, 2020Business programs receive ACBSP accreditationNovember 24, 2020Priority scholarship deadline now Jan. 15November 20, 2020December CommencementsNovember 19, 2020Milligan senior directs Shakespeare play entirely on ZoomNovember 18, 2020Milligan sees lowest tuition increase in 30 yearsNovember 13, 2020 Close
Request Info
Give to Milligan
Milligan Today
Privacy Policy
This privacy policy has been compiled to better serve those who are concerned with how their ‘Personally identifiable information’ (PII) is being used online. PII, as used in US privacy law and information security, is information that can be used on its own or with other information to identify, contact, or locate a single person, or to identify an individual in context. Please read our privacy policy carefully to get a clear understanding of how we collect, use, protect or otherwise handle your Personally Identifiable Information in accordance with our website.
What personal information do we collect from the people that visit our blog, website or app?
When ordering or registering on our site, as appropriate, you may be asked to enter your name, email address, mailing address, phone number or other details to help you with your experience.
When do we collect information?
We collect information from you when you fill out a form or enter information on our site.
How do we use your information?
We may use the information we collect from you when you register, make a purchase, sign up for our newsletter, respond to a survey or marketing communication, surf the website, or use certain other site features in the following ways:
To quickly process your transactions.
To send periodic emails regarding your order or other products and services.
How do we protect visitor information?
We do not use vulnerability scanning and/or scanning to PCI standards.
We use regular Malware Scanning.
Your personal information is contained behind secured networks and is only accessible by a limited number of persons who have special access rights to such systems, and are required to keep the information confidential. In addition, all sensitive/credit information you supply is encrypted via Secure Socket Layer (SSL) technology.
We implement a variety of security measures when a user places an order enters, submits, or accesses their information to maintain the safety of your personal information.
All transactions are processed through a gateway provider and are not stored or processed on our servers.
Do we use ‘cookies’?
Yes. Cookies are small files that a site or its service provider transfers to your computer’s hard drive through your Web browser (if you allow) that enables the site’s or service provider’s systems to recognize your browser and capture and remember certain information. For instance, we use cookies to help us remember and process the items in your shopping cart. They are also used to help us understand your preferences based on previous or current site activity, which enables us to provide you with improved services. We also use cookies to help us compile aggregate data about site traffic and site interaction so that we can offer better site experiences and tools in the future.
We use cookies to:
Compile aggregate data about site traffic and site interactions in order to offer better site experiences and tools in the future. We may also use trusted third party services that track this information on our behalf.
You can choose to have your computer warn you each time a cookie is being sent, or you can choose to turn off all cookies. You do this through your browser (like Internet Explorer) settings. Each browser is a little different, so look at your browser’s Help menu to learn the correct way to modify your cookies.
If you disable cookies off, some features will be disabled It won’t affect the users experience that make your site experience more efficient and some of our services will not function properly.
However, you can still place orders.
Third Party Disclosure
We do not sell, trade, or otherwise transfer to outside parties your personally identifiable information unless we provide you with advance notice. This does not include website hosting partners and other parties who assist us in operating our website, conducting our business, or servicing you, so long as those parties agree to keep this information confidential. We may also release your information when we believe release is appropriate to comply with the law, enforce our site policies, or protect ours or others’ rights, property, or safety.
However, non-personally identifiable visitor information may be provided to other parties for marketing, advertising, or other uses.
Third party links
We do not include or offer third party products or services on our website.
Adroll
As you browse www.Milligan.edu advertising cookies will be placed on your computer so that we can understand what you are interested in. Our display advertising partner, AdRoll, then enables us to present you with retargeting advertising on other sites based on your previous interaction with [company website]. The techniques our partners employ do not collect personal information such as your name, email address, postal address, or telephone number. You can visit this page to opt out of AdRoll’s and their partners’ targeted advertising.
Google
Google’s advertising requirements can be summed up by Google’s Advertising Principles. They are put in place to provide a positive experience for users. https://support.google.com/adwordspolicy/answer/1316548?hl=en
We use Google AdSense Advertising on our website.
Google, as a third party vendor, uses cookies to serve ads on our site. Google’s use of the DART cookie enables it to serve ads to our users based on their visit to our site and other sites on the Internet. Users may opt out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the Google ad and content network privacy policy.
We have implemented the following:
Remarketing with Google AdSense
Google Display Network Impression Reporting
Demographics and Interests Reporting
DoubleClick Platform Integration
We along with third-party vendors, such as Google use first-party cookies (such as the Google Analytics cookies) and third-party cookies (such as the DoubleClick cookie) or other third-party identifiers together to compile data regarding user interactions with ad impressions, and other ad service functions as they relate to our website.
Opting out:
Users can set preferences for how Google advertises to you using the Google Ad Settings page. Alternatively, you can opt out by visiting the Network Advertising initiative opt out page or permanently using the Google Analytics Opt Out Browser add on.
California Online Privacy Protection Act
CalOPPA is the first state law in the nation to require commercial websites and online services to post a privacy policy. The law’s reach stretches well beyond California to require a person or company in the United States (and conceivably the world) that operates websites collecting personally identifiable information from California consumers to post a conspicuous privacy policy on its website stating exactly the information being collected and those individuals with whom it is being shared, and to comply with this policy. – See more at: http://consumercal.org/california-online-privacy-protection-act-caloppa/#sthash.0FdRbT51.dpuf
According to CalOPPA we agree to the following:
Users can visit our site anonymously
Once this privacy policy is created, we will add a link to it on our home page, or as a minimum on the first significant page after entering our website.
Our Privacy Policy link includes the word ‘Privacy’, and can be easily be found on the page specified above.
Users will be notified of any privacy policy changes:
On our Privacy Policy Page
Users are able to change their personal information:
By emailing us
By calling us
By logging in to their account
By chatting with us or sending us a ticket
How does our site handle do not track signals?
We honor do not track signals and do not track, plant cookies, or use advertising when a Do Not Track (DNT) browser mechanism is in place.
Does our site allow third party behavioral tracking?
It’s also important to note that we allow third party behavioral tracking
COPPA (Children Online Privacy Protection Act)
When it comes to the collection of personal information from children under 13, the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA) puts parents in control. The Federal Trade Commission, the nation’s consumer protection agency, enforces the COPPA Rule, which spells out what operators of websites and online services must do to protect children’s privacy and safety online.
We do not specifically market to children under 13.
Fair Information Practices
The Fair Information Practices Principles form the backbone of privacy law in the United States and the concepts they include have played a significant role in the development of data protection laws around the globe. Understanding the Fair Information Practice Principles and how they should be implemented is critical to comply with the various privacy laws that protect personal information.
In order to be in line with Fair Information Practices we will take the following responsive action, should a data breach occur:
We will notify the users via email
Within 7 business days
We also agree to the individual redress principle, which requires that individuals have a right to pursue legally enforceable rights against data collectors and processors who fail to adhere to the law. This principle requires not only that individuals have enforceable rights against data users, but also that individuals have recourse to courts or a government agency to investigate and/or prosecute non-compliance by data processors.
CAN SPAM Act
The CAN-SPAM Act is a law that sets the rules for commercial email, establishes requirements for commercial messages, gives recipients the right to have emails stopped from being sent to them, and spells out tough penalties for violations.
We collect your email address in order to:
Send information, respond to inquiries, and/or other requests or questions.
To be in accordance with CANSPAM we agree to the following:
NOT use false, or misleading subjects or email addresses
Identify the message as an advertisement in some reasonable way
Include the physical address of our business or site headquarters
Monitor third party email marketing services for compliance, if one is used.
Honor opt-out/unsubscribe requests quickly
Allow users to unsubscribe by using the link at the bottom of each email
If at any time you would like to unsubscribe from receiving future emails, you can and we will promptly remove you from ALL correspondence.
Contacting Us
If there are any questions regarding this privacy policy you may contact us using the information below.
Milligan University
1 Blowers Boulevard
Milligan, TN 37682
423.461.8700
